

# George Christodoulou

N. Zerva, 45332 Ioannina, Greece Contact via email: g.christodoulou@uoi.gr

Contact via phone: +306973180106

Contact online: github.com/GiorgosChristodoulou linkedin.com/in/george-ch

### **SUMMARY**

I received my diploma in Computer Science and Engineering from the Computer Science and Engineering Department of the University of Ioannina in 2017. I received my MSc in Computer Science with specialization in software from the Computer Science and Engineering Department of the University of Ioannina in 2020. My research interests include Data Management and Query processing (Efficient Data Indexing and Retrieval on temporal data). Currently, I am pursuing my PhD degree from the Computer Science and Engineering Department of the University of Ioannina.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Research Assistant at Centre for <b>Research &amp; Technology Hellas (CERTH)</b> • worked on designing and developing an Anomaly detector based on machine learning techniques for the 'Secure and Safe IoT' (SerIoT) project.  • Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow	May 2019 - Sep 2019
Software engineer Intern at Natech S.A., Ioannina, Greece  • worked on designing and developing a ASP.NET MVC web application • C#, MVC	Jul 2016 - Aug 2016
Networks lab assistant at <b>University of Ioannina</b> , <b>Department of Computer Science &amp; Engineering</b> , <b>Greece</b>	Oct 2017 - Jan 2018 Oct 2018 - Jan2019
Java lab assistant at University of Ioannina, Department of Computer Science & Engineering, Greece	Mar 2018 - June 2018

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Ioannina, Department of Computer Science & Engineering , Greece

Diploma in Computer Science & Engineering

Python lab assistant at **University of Ioannina**,

→ Grade: 6.74

**Department of Computer** 

Science & Engineering, Greece

- → thesis: Routing Methods with Machine Learning on Delay Tolerant Networks.
  - Redesign and optimization of a routing protocol with machine learning techniques, C++

Sep 2011 - Sep 2017

Oct 2019 - Jan 2022

- MSc in Computer Science & Engineering
  - → Grade: 9.08
     → thesis: A Prefix-based Hybrid Solution for Main
  - → thesis: A Prefix-based Hybrid Solution for Main Memory Indexing
    - Development of Main memory Index with binary representations of data, C++
- Currently pursuing PhD in Computer Science & Engineering

Feb 2020 - Present

Oct 2017- Feb 2020

- → Advisory Committee :
  - Prof. Nikolaos Mamoulis (Supervisor)
  - Prof. Panagiotis Vasiliadis
  - Prof. Panagiotis Tsaparas

### **PUBLICATIONS**

George Christodoulou, Panagiotis Bouros and Nikos Mamoulis:

HINT: A Hierarchical Index for Intervals in Main Memory

Proceedings of the 2022 ACM International Conference on Management of Data (**ACM SIGMOD**), Philadelphia, PA, USA, June 12-17, 2022

George Christodoulou, Panagiotis Bouros and Nikos Mamoulis:

HINT: A Hierarchical Interval Index for Allen Relationships

Under Review, 2022

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

C++ - used at university courses, my BSc thesis, my MSc thesis, PhD

Python - used at university courses, CERTH, PhD

Java (SE, EE) – used at university courses and various projects

**C#** - used at Natech S.A.

**Database management** - used at university courses

**Machine learning techniques** – used at multiple university courses, my BSc thesis, CERTH

**Tensorflow, PyTorch** – used at CERTH

Linux - used at university courses

ASP.NET MVC - used at Natech S.A.

# OTHER SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Languages Greek (native), English (fluent), Dutch (fluent)

Interests Interval Data Indexing and retrieval, Spatial Data indexing and

retrieval, Machine Learning